[♪ cheerful music playing]
[narrator] Noel is a member of
Travis Japan, a Japanese dance music group
that has achieved success
in the United States.
He is also a certified
international tour conductor.
Noel sets out on a solo trip
before the rest of the band members
to plan a summer vacation for them.
He wants to make it
the group's best summer break ever!
[Chaka]
We'll have fun all the way to Moab.
-Agreed?
-[all] Agreed!
-"I've booked a hotel in Las Vegas."
-Not here.
-[Genta exclaims]
-[clapping]
[in English] Let's go!
-Let's go!
-[Shime] Let's go! Babe.
[Shizu, in Japanese] Oh! It moved.
Nice! You're driving on American roads!
[Chaka] Good golly.
[narrator] It's a special summer break
Noel organized
for the Travis Japan members.
Their adventure through the
Southwestern United States finally begins.
At the foot of the Rocky Mountains
where the desert winds blow
lies the real America
the members have yet to see.
Their final destination is
Sedona, Arizona.
The members will split into two groups
and drive separately toward their goal.
Noel sets out to Sedona on his own
before the others
to quietly prepare
a warm welcome for them.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
Travis Japan
SUMMER VACATION!! IN THE USA
[♪ tranquil music playing]
[Noel] First, I want everyone to
experience how grand America is.
Nature of this scale
will make them feel like a speck.
It will lead to the team's growth.
But you know how they are.
They may simply enjoy the road trip,
completely oblivious to my intentions.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[narrator, in English]
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
[in Japanese]
Team B embarks on their journey,
but not before a quick detour.
-[Genta] Awesome.
-[Shime] There's a beef jerky shop.
[narrator] Shime, Genta, and Machu
decide to grab a bite
before they hit the road.
[Machu] I've got a good feeling
about this place.
[Shime, in English] Thank you.
-[Shime] Awesome. Cool.
-[clerk] Hi, Hello.
[Machu] Pretty good.
-[Genta] Awesome.
-[Shime] Wow!
[Genta] This whole place smells like meat.
[narrator] Team B makes a pit stop
at a shop offering homemade jerky.
Jerky is local to New Mexico.
It is known for its thin slices
and dried texture.
It comes in many varieties.
[in English] Do you have no… not sweet?
-[clerk] No sweet?
-To, like, try…
-So, like, try?
-[Genta] Yes.
-[Shime] Salty…
-Okay.
So this right here, is the green chili.
-[Machu] Thank you so much.
-This is mostly what we're popular for
here in Albuquerque and New Mexico.
[Genta] Mmm!
-[clerk] It's really, really hot.
-Is it spicy?
-Yeah. Really hot.
-[Genta] I'll try. I'll try.
-[clerk] You want to try that one?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Is it spicy?
-It's outta this world.
-[clerk] Try this too?
-Yeah. I'll try.
-[Genta] Let's try a bit.
-Time for a bite.
Digging in.
It's not what I expected.
[exclaims]
-Oh!
-[clerk chuckles]
So spi… Hot.
So spicy.
[clerk] Yeah.
And it gets more hotter at the end.
More at the end, more of it comes.
-Sheesh!
-It's ridiculously spicy.
[clerk] It creeps up on you.
-So spicy. Yes.
-[clerk] Yeah, it's hot.
-But, I love that.
-The best in the whole shop,
in my opinion, the "Takis" is really good.
Just… You guys should try "Breaking Bad."
[Genta] Breaking Bad.
-Breaking Bad.
-[Machu] Wow, look at its color.
-This one's been popular for a long time.
-[Machu] Sick.
-[Shime] What is it?
-Like turquoise?
-Yeah.
-[chuckles]
-Oh!
-Beautiful.
-Thank you so much.
-Yeah, "Takis."
Thank you.
[clerk] It tastes different.
-Scrumptious.
-Mmm.
-Good taste. Cookie? Like…
-Right. Yeah.
Like cook… Oh! Mm-hmm.
Like cookie.
-Like cookie…
-Yeah. Mmm.
-Yum.
-This is good.
[Machu]
The beef jerky's culture is traditional?
-Yeah. Yeah.
-Is it?
When jerky first started it was, like,
in the… Like, long, long time ago.
-Uh-huh.
-1580 or something like that.
-Native Americans.
-I see. I see.
-I see.
A long, long time ago.
And then, like, the 1800s,
we started doing it with
the Spanish and stuff like that.
And, you know,
over the years it's evolved.
And people have opened up shops
and stuff like that out here.
-Native Americans always eat it? This.
-Yes.
Oh.
-I see.
-[clerk] Yeah.
[client] Right? Is that what I got?
You did. You got red…
Thank you for your patience, again.
-I appreciate you.
-You're welcome. You're welcome.
-You eat beef jerky?
-Yes.
-Always?
-How…
Not always. But we like to stop by.
It's a nice…
My kids like it.
-Your kids?
-Hi!
-The little one over there.
[band members] Hi. Hello. Hello.
-[Genta] What do you like? Flavors.
-[Shime] Cute.
[client] She wanted us to stop today.
-What's your favorite flavor?
-[Shime] Yes.
Taki.
-Taki? Yeah.
-[Machu] Taki? Ah! Yeah. Nice.
-Have you eaten a lot of food from here?
-[Machu] No. The…
-Like, traditional food. Like…
-We've never…
-We've never been to here. First time.
-Yeah. First time.
[client]
You gotta go eat some traditional food.
-What do we want to get?
-Like, red chili.
-Red chili.
-Red chili. Yes.
-You'll like it. Maybe, like…
-Yes.
-You ready?
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
-Thank you. Take care.
-[chuckles]
[Genta, in Japanese] Whoa, cool.
[narrator]
In this region where dry winds blow,
rich ranching culture flourished.
With it came the wisdom to
preserve buffalo meat through drying.
To this day,
this area is home to many jerky shops
preserving traditional
meat-curing techniques.
-[Machu] Oh!
-[Shime] Wow! Amazing.
-[clerk, in English] This is full.
-Full, full.
It gets a little bit fuller. But this
is mostly when a container's full.
[Machu] Mm-hmm.
So our Teriyakis and Raspberries
are gonna be really heavy.
-So, pick it up a little bit. Pick it up.
-Mm-hmm.
All right.
-[in Japanese] Crap! Seriously…
-[clerk chuckles]
-[in English] Very heavy.
-Yeah, it's so heavy.
[in Japanese] That's heavy.
It's extremely heavy.
[in English] So that's why
the heavy ones stay on the bottom.
I don't know why I love it. I just…
It's something I liked
when I started doing it with my dad.
So that's what makes me happy,
is, remembering my dad.
[Machu] Mm-hmm.
-That's him up there on the wall.
-Oh!
[clerk] I do. I love coming to work
every day. It's my passion for sure.
-Yeah.
-[Shime] Ah.
-It's nice. Great.
-Peaceful.
-Yes.
-[chuckles]
-[clerk] Yeah, it's peaceful.
-Peaceful.
[Genta] Who knew
jerky came in so many flavors?
-[Shime] It's not a thing in Japan.
-Not really.
[Machu] Not at all.
[Genta] I've never even considered jerky
with different flavors.
-These flavors can only be found here.
-[Shime] That's true.
[Genta] Yeah.
[narrator] Team B is finally heading out
to Las Vegas.
[Shime] It's open out here.
[Genta] It's amazing.
I like this feeling of vast openness.
[Machu] It's refreshing.
-The nature is majestic.
-[Machu] It's peaceful too.
[Genta] I know what you mean.
-You've got the hang of it, Machu.
-You think so?
[Shime] You're a natural.
A few years ago,
I would've never imagined
going on a road trip outside of Japan.
[Machu chuckles] I can relate. No joke.
-[Genta] This is so great.
-[Machu] Yeah.
-Hey, Shime.
-[Shime] What's that?
How does my posture look from the side?
-You've got excellent posture.
-[laughing]
-[Genta] Really?
-Your posture is perfect.
-[Genta laughing] Your posture is perfect.
-[laughing]
You're not slouching at all.
[Genta] You nailed the distance
to the steering wheel.
Wait, don't I look cool?
Not really.
[both laughing]
[Machu] I feel watched.
-Step on it, Machu.
-I am!
Face the front, Machu.
I am!
-I need to focus, the road is winding.
-[all laughing]
-[laughing]
-[Machu] It's a winding road.
[Noel, in Japanese] Team A takes in
the magnificence of Mother Nature.
Team B's trip focuses on American culture
tucked away in the countryside.
Those are supposed to be
the trips' themes,
but more importantly,
this is their summer break.
At first,
I want everyone to simply enjoy their trip
without thinking too much into it.
[Shizu] You nervous?
Crazy. Chaka's driving on American roads.
[Shizu] So cool.
-[Umi] You've got great posture too.
-[Shizu laughs]
[Umi, in English] So… big!
[in Japanese] Look at this view.
Amazing.
I'm starting to get hyped.
[Shizu]
Let's take in the be-Utah-ful scenery.
-[Chaka] Yeah! Wanna walk around a bit?
-[Umi] Ooh!
-[Shizu laughs] Yeah, let's.
-[Umi] I'll ride.
[narrator, in English] Moab, Utah.
[in Japanese]
Moab is a gateway town to national parks.
After driving for eight hours
from Salt Lake City,
Team A finally arrives at Moab.
The visitors stay here as they
make their way to national parks.
[Umi] Look at that buggy car.
And that's, like,
their rendition of WALL-E.
-[Chaka] It's crazy.
-[Umi] What's that? Look.
[narrator] The trio makes a detour at a
fossil shop on their way to the campsite.
-Look.
-They have fossils.
[narrator] Moab Rock Shop.
Just as the name suggests,
this is a crystal shop.
The owner opened this shop 60 years ago
after he discovered dinosaur fossils
in this area.
It's grown into a popular shop
where locals and tourists flock to buy
fossils, crystals, and ores from Utah.
-[Chaka, Shizu] Hello. Hello. Hello. Yes…
-Whoa, look.
-[Umi] This is amazing.
-[Chaka] Wow!
-[Shizu] Gemstones.
-[Umi] Holy moly.
[Shizu] Cute.
[Chaka] Creepy.
Look, they've got fossils.
-[Shizu] You're right.
-Fossils of what?
[Shizu] What's this?
[Umi] Huh? Look at this.
-[Chaka, in English] Not for sell.
-[Umi] What's that?
-[in Japanese] Some kind of snake?
-Snake.
[Chaka] Can you see this one?
-[Shizu] This is unreal. Whoa.
-[Umi] Stone snake.
[Shizu, in English] "Ice Age."
-Oh, my gosh, see that? "Mammoth teeth."
-[Umi] Hmm?
-It's kinda big, isn't it? Freaking huge.
-It says "Ice Age,"
-like the prehistoric times.
-Is it a mammoth tooth from the Ice Age?
-[Umi] Wow.
-Mammoths must've been gigantic.
-[Chaka] Ancient…
-Whoa. This is so beautiful.
[Chaka] That's probably another fossil.
-Reminds me of a gyotaku fish print.
-[Umi] Yeah.
[Shizu] How interesting.
[Chaka] They can tell this area used to be
underwater from these fossils.
[Shizu] This region, yeah.
-Is that a part of a claw?
-Creepy.
Wow… Awesome.
-Look, Dwayne "The Rock" Johnson.
-[chuckling]
[Umi] Maybe the shop owner's a fan of his.
[Shizu laughing] What the heck.
Awesome.
Didn't we all dream of owning
rocks like these as kids?
What events led these rocks
to end up in this color?
Surely there's a scientific explanation,
but…
It's incredible to consider,
as inhabitants of planet Earth.
Let's see if there's anything
with all of our colors.
Nope.
This one kind of has them.
Since I stumbled upon
these accessories here…
These are both made by Native Americans.
We came out here and bought these.
If we wear them, then maybe we'll attach
a special meaning to them later on.
[Shizu] Noel.
Shime, Machu, Chaka.
Genta, Shizu, Umi.
Yes, green for Umi. These will do.
Perfect.
You're a big boy.
-[in English] Hi.
-[client] Hi.
-Yeah, you can pet him.
-Really?
[client] Of course.
-Where are you guys from?
-Japan.
Are you gonna go white water rafting
down the river?
We never try that.
-Yeah.
-They got…
-That's good. That's a good trip.
-That's good?
And then, also,
if you want to learn like canyoneering
or learn about rock climbing
and canyoneering
they have schools here and they teach you…
they take you out into the desert
and they take you up mountains
and you climb mountains
and they teach you how to do it.
-We wanna do that.
-It's a really good thing that
it's one of the few places in the world
you can really go
and get good stuff like that.
[Shizu] Thank you. Thank you.
[in Japanese] This is for you, Umi.
Ah.
-Don't look like you don't want it.
-[chuckles]
Here's red for you.
-Cool, thanks.
-Red…
-Jasper.
-Jasper?
It's a gift.
-Thanks.
I also got this necklace and bracelet.
-This is the bracelet.
-Sweet.
These rocks look distinct to this region,
don't you think? I mean their color.
Yeah, this reddish color
reminds me of this region.
-Shizu, you were drawn to it, weren't you?
-Yeah, I really liked it.
You took interest in it
when we first stepped in.
I love this shade of white.
It's so pretty.
I chose it because I found
its translucent color striking.
I love that.
-[in English] Hi, it's been a while.
-[client] Yeah, it's been a while.
[band members laughing]
-I'll show you what… Last night…
-Yeah.
Or early this morning,
I was out in an area called Yellow Cat,
I was digging for… called coprolite.
Coprolite?
Yes. It's fossilized dinosaur poop.
-Dinosaur poo?
-Yeah.
-[laughs]
-From dinosaurs.
[Chaka] It's so funny.
[Shizu] Wow.
-It's fossilized.
-Smell. Smell.
-So it's just rock.
-[laughs]
But it's… that's what that is.
It's called coprolite.
-Wow.
-Coprolite.
-It's so beautiful.
-Those are for you. For you guys.
-Really?
-Yeah. Take them with you. Have fun.
-Thank you.
-Oh, my gosh.
-It's a precious one. I love it so much.
-Thank you.
-I got a big bag full of them. So…
-Thank you so much. Good to see you.
-Take care. All right. Enjoy your meet--
-Thanks so much.
-Thank you very much.
-Now, that's good stuff. I agree.
-Thank you. Thank you.
Enjoy your trip. Be safe.
-Yes, you too.
-Thank you.
Come on, Max.
Bye. Bye, Max. See ya.
[in Japanese]
That's another one for the books.
He said we can have these.
Pose for the camera!
-Yay!
-[whoops]
-[Umi, in Japanese] During our training…
-[Shizu] No kidding.
[narrator] Food is part of what makes
an RV adventure exciting.
The trio makes a stop at
Moab's super-sized grocery store.
[Umi] Bian Li, see.
[Chaka] Chinese?
[Shizu] Heave-ho.
-What about this one? You want this out?
-[Umi] Just leave it there.
What if they don't all fit?
-And these?
-These probably don't need to be put away.
-It wasn't in the refrigerated section.
-But once we open it,
-it needs to be stored in the fridge.
-Guess so.
[Shizu] Crap. This heat's killing me.
[Umi] This body care product…
Oh, it sticks out.
Maybe it'll fit better in here instead.
[Umi] No, you can just put it here.
[Shizu] Wanna put away a few cans?
-All done.
We managed to fit them all.
Man, shopping was fun.
Yeah, it was kinda exciting.
It's been a while since we've…
We were like this when we first moved.
We were like this on our day one
of training abroad.
Takes me back.
-We might've overdone it.
-We mostly bought drinks.
-[Chaka] Well, drinks get me hyped up.
-[Shizu] I get you.
The supermarket gets me going.
I get too hyped.
You end up tossing
all sorts of things in your cart.
Look.
Fully loaded.
[Umi] Look at all the breakfast items.
We grabbed a good selection of 'em.
[Shizu] Yeah. Right?
[Umi] And also, see this?
TV dinners.
We haven't tried many frozen meals
in the US yet.
So I'm excited for this opportunity
to sample some.
-[objects clattering]
-[exclaiming]
[Chaka] This is why I said…
-[Umi] Gotta put more stuff away.
-[Shizu] What do we do about these?
It's a major incident.
-[Shizu laughs]
-[Chaka] What a disaster.
[Umi] All right.
Let's get to cleaning.
[Shizu] Time to pick up.
What should go first?
For starters, the perishables
should be refrigerated.
[Chaka, Umi] Yeah.
-[Shizu] And…
-[Umi] Like this?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-[Umi] Wanna put it in too?
A one-two.
Hup.
[Shizu] That covers the essentials.
-[Shizu] Will it close?
-Let's find the lock.
[Shizu] Lock? The door shouldn't
spring open if it's closed properly.
-[clicks]
-Hear that? It clicked.
And…
-[Chaka] There.
-[Shizu] Yeah.
It wasn't closed properly.
[Shizu] Who was it?
Who opened it last?
[Shizu] Wasn't me.
I said "Look at all the drinks"…
-No… Did I?
-…and you closed it.
[Shizu] It wasn't me.
-[rewinding sound]
-[Shizu] Give me a minute… there.
-[Chaka] This will do.
-[Shizu] Here.
-And this…
-Sorry.
-You're quick to apologize.
-In a split-second. It's no biggie.
-What about the top?
-It probably locks the same way.
-Wonder what makes it click? This part.
-Right here.
-[Shizu] My bad, guys. Sorry.
-[chuckling]
[♪ whimsical music playing]
[music stops]
[Shizu] We're relying on you.
[Umi] Whoa!
It's the real deal. A real camping ground.
[Shizu] Amazing. There's so many RVs here.
[Umi] I've never been
to a place like this before.
[Shizu] Where's number eight?
Where's our spot? Where is it?
Right over there.
The numbers are written on tiny plates.
[Chaka] Six. Six.
-[Umi] Where is it?
-[Shizu] Seven. Back it up nicely.
-All right!
-[Umi] Can I make it? Can I?
-Will I make it? Hey, do I have room?
-Careful. Does the car fit?
-Gotta make it fit even if it doesn't.
-[Shizu laughs]
-I'll try.
-[Chaka] Okay.
[Umi] Hold on. Steer to the right. You're
leaning left. There's space to the right.
-[Chaka] I'm not straight.
-[Umi] Coach.
Go, go, go, go. Look,
a car's coming. Let's park around here.
[Chaka] Is here good?
-[Umi] Okay!
-[clapping]
-[Shizu] All right. Nice.
-[Chaka] We have arrived.
-[Umi] This seems to be our campsite.
-[Shizu] Thanks.
[Umi] Thank you for driving.
-[Umi] I'll go set the drinks out.
-Whoa!
-[Shizu] Yeah!
-[thudding]
-[Umi] Whoa!
[narrator] Team A
has arrived at the campsite where
they will be spending the night.
[Shizu] I'm speechless.
[Chaka] What a magnificent view.
[in Japanese] It's the morning of day two.
The Team A trio is brewing coffee.
-[Umi] This is sick.
-The water's ready.
[Shizu] 'Kay.
-I've never done this before.
-Me neither.
-All right, coffee time.
-Yeah.
-I got us something special.
-He's totally checked out.
-Where is it from?
-Moab. It's from
-this shop in Moab.
-These beans are from this shop.
-[Shizu] Coffee beans.
-[Chaka] I found it at a café.
-[Umi] Really?
-[Chaka] "Rockstar."
[Shizu] I love the vibe.
Ground coffee beans.
How many spoonfuls do I use?
-How about three? Three sounds right.
-About three?
-[Shizu] Three.
-I'm not the one you should be asking.
[Chaka laughs]
Well, let's use three spoonfuls for now.
-See how it tastes.
-We'll go with three. Give me a minute.
-Care to get a whiff?
-This smells incredible.
-The aroma is part of the experience.
-[Chaka] Yeah, I smell coffee.
[metal cups clinking]
Oh, the aroma is fantastic.
It hits the spot.
Let's start day two
by waking up to a cup of coffee.
Huh.
[Umi] It's a bit heavy.
-[Chaka] Is it?
-Yeah.
I don't do well with hot drinks.
But it's my kinda coffee.
[narrator] Noel's travel guide notebook
comes to mind.
[Chaka] Today will be
another day filled with activities.
[Shizu] We have activities?
We've got missions to accomplish today?
[Chaka] Indeed we do.
Take a look at this page.
Ta-da.
"Moab."
We can go off-roading or biking.
We're supposed to enjoy
-recreational activities here.
-[Umi] Yeah. Okay.
Noel wants us to thoroughly enjoy…
-[Shizu] Activities at this campsite.
-[Chaka] Enjoy activities.
-[Shizu] Seriously?
-[Chaka] I think that's the plan.
Today's a day off then.
Exactly. So we have
the entire day to ourselves.
There's no driving involved today
since we're already here at Moab.
-We're enjoying the day here.
-We're supposed to just have fun today.
We'll explore the area…
-We'll explore.
-…and conclude the day…
-With some BBQ.
-It's gonna be a great day! Yeah!
[sighs]
[Chaka] So today,
we're gonna hang out around here.
[Umi] Yeah.
[playing drums]
[narrator] Team A spends the day relaxing
while Team B
makes their drive to Las Vegas.
[Machu] Those clouds… Those
lightning strikes are something else.
[Shime] For real.
Seriously, those lightning bolts
are terrifying.
It was bright and sunny just a minute ago.
[Machu] Two, one, swish.
[exclaims]
-Swoosh, swoosh.
-[Shime, in English] Wiper in America.
[chuckling] Wiper in America.
[Shime, in Japanese] See over there?
There's blue sky on the other side.
Must be nice over there.
[Machu] Look, it's already letting up.
Summon the squall, Genta.
Yeah. It's beautiful.
It feels otherworldly.
[Machu] We're leaving the squall already.
-[Genta] So quickly?
-[Machu] Awesome.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[Umi] Let's go!
Basketball is my favorite sport.
[Shizu laughs]
-Of course it's a dunk.
-[Chaka] Can I be defense?
Sure.
[Chaka] Man, you're good.
You're a beast! That's what's up.
-[Umi] He's too good.
-[Chaka] Such a beast.
-So good!
-[Umi] That's sick.
Let's give it a proper shot.
Here I come.
You can make a dunk.
-[exclaims]
-[Chaka] Nice.
[exclaims, laughs]
[Umi] Ah! Score! [laughs]
[Shizu] Chaka, you slick little…
Who are you up against?
[Shizu]
You're only moving sideways, not forward.
Good going!
Like a pro.
[Umi] He's quick as a rabbit.
Shizu, you face him now.
[Chaka shouts]
-What went wrong?
-Don't steal the ball, okay?
-[cheering]
-[Shizu] That's rad.
-[Umi] Oh, sweet.
-Nice shot.
-[Umi] Oh!
-[Chaka] Whoa.
Crap.
[pants]
[Shizu] It's too hot.
[Umi pants]
Swipe with your fingers. Take it.
Here.
-Thanks.
-It doesn't make any difference.
What do you mean, use my nail?
[Chaka] See? Doesn't work. [laughs]
[song continues]
[cheering]
[song ends]
Let's go pool!
[cheering]
Let's go pool! [grunts, shouting]
Cannonball!
[screams]
[Shizu] The water's freezing cold!
[Chaka exclaims]
Feels great.
[Shizu] I can't swim. I panicked.
Forgot I can't swim.
Whoo!
[Shizu laughs]
It's a bubble gun!
[exclaiming]
Coming this way?
-[Umi] Oh, shoot!
-[Shizu] Geez!
[Shizu, Umi laughing] He's coming,
zoom, zoom! He's coming. He's super fast.
His speed is insane!
[laughing]
-[Umi] Whoo!
-[exclaims]
-Man, that was a blast.
-It really was.
-I had loads of fun.
-I love the water.
It's been a while
since we hung out at a pool like this.
This takes me back.
-Since what, Hawaii?
-I'd say.
This is starting
to feel like summer break.
-That's because it is.
-Well, yeah.
Right?
I'm feelin' summer vacation vibes.
We're enjoying a proper break.
-There's BBQ to look forward to, right?
-[Chaka] That's the plan.
Is it okay we're having so much fun?
Wanna get going?
-Let's go.
-Let's go. Good.
-Let's go before it gets dark.
-I second that.
[Shizu] Although I don't mind the dark.
It's more classy that way.
[Chaka]
Think dinner prep will take a while?
[Umi, in Japanese] Look, an ice cream
shop. Never mind, they're gelato.
-I want some.
-After all…
[Umi] They have espresso too.
-It'll be so tasty.
-[Chaka, in English] Hello.
-Hello.
-[Umi] Whoa, the chocolate looks great.
-[Chaka] I hear what…
What the most… the best sell?
The most popular I would say is espresso.
-Espresso? Yeah?
-[Chaka] Uh-huh.
It's more popular. You wanna sample it?
See if you wanna get it?
-Really? Yes, please.
-Yeah, of course. All right.
-Espresso.
-Thank you.
[in Japanese] That's a solid choice.
I may go for the espresso.
-[in English] Thank you.
-Yep.
It's so great.
Mmm.
[clerk] Delicious, right?
-Yes. Yeah. So good.
-I love it.
-Can I get the small? In a cup?
-Of course. Yeah. Yep, of course.
Cup of espresso…
and can I mix?
-Yep. Yeah, of course. You can mix it.
-Okay. And then, chocolate. Yeah.
[clerk] Chocolate? Perfect.
-Can I get lemon and mango?
-Of course.
And mango? In a small one as well?
-The large.
-Large? Yeah.
Thank you.
[Umi, in Japanese] Look.
-[Shizu] Talk about a large.
-[Umi] They're loading it up.
[Shizu laughs] Just wow.
[clerk] There's that one.
Wow! Thank you!
I finally… uh…
Can I get espresso and chocolate
on the waffle cone, please?
-On the waffle cone? Yeah, I can do that.
-[Shizu] Waffle cone.
-Thank you.
-Thanks so much.
-[Shizu] Thank you.
-That's huge, huh? Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-[clerk] Yeah. Have a good one.
-Yeah, you too.
-[clerk] Bye.
-Have a good one.
[clerk] Bye. Thank you.
[door opens]
[Umi, in Japanese] Let's eat it quickly.
[Shizu] Time to dig in.
-Cheers.
-My cone's loaded.
The lemon is refreshing.
The worker was so kind to us.
You guys wanna sample it?
See if you wanna get it?
-Really? Yes, please.
-Yeah, of course. All right.
We've run into many kind-hearted people.
I guess they strike up conversations
to try to get to know us.
Their curiosity shows their kindness.
It encourages me to reciprocate in return.
I've enjoyed their friendliness.
It's the little things.
Sometimes I make eye contact
with a stranger as we cross paths…
And if it was in Japan, we'd ignore
each other and carry on with our day.
We don't greet strangers. But here,
an eye contact leads to a "Hello."
It may not be a full-on greeting, but they
give us simple acknowledgements.
A single act of kindness really shows…
Let's see, this may be a weird way
to put it, but they greet someone like me.
They take the time to notice
someone like me and say hello.
Out here, I really notice the kindness
like Shizuya mentioned,
as well as their hospitality.
We're not from around here.
So we don't know
what this place is really like.
But strangers come up to us
and ask where we're from.
They ask us about our experiences here,
as well as the other places we've been to.
The locals here ask
"What was that city like?"
It makes me feel so accepted and at home
because they take the time
to ask questions.
Although we're complete strangers
passing through,
the locals have shown interest in us,
and that makes me feel welcomed.
It's very…
Being interested is how they show
that your presence is appreciated.
Even a simple "welcome" from people
motivates me to respond with confidence.
These…
How do I put it?
These personal interactions.
I want to incorporate
that friendliness into my life too.
This is a heartwarming place.
It's growing into a spot
I want to visit again.
I love camping. It's my hobby,
and I try to go every chance I get.
That's how much I love to camp.
I even purchased my very own camping lot.
I don't want to force it on anyone,
but some of the members
would rather be at home
and play video games all day.
Or, while some members
are interested in the idea of it,
at the same time,
it's intimidating to them.
I want those members to see
what makes camping so incredibly fun.
To be honest, I've never tried
camping in the United States.
-It's hard to know what they'll think.
-All right, here we go!
-Time to get the grill fired up!
-Let's have a cookout.
[Umi] Let's do it.
Seriously, I'll be in charge of the meat.
-[Shizu] Yeah! I'm counting on you.
-We're in good hands.
-As usual, I'll handle the meat.
-We're looking forward to it.
-We've got our meat lover.
-And…
[Umi] Meat tastes better
with an extra dash of salt and pepper.
[Chaka] I second that.
-That's what I'm talking about.
-[Shizu] You know it.
Those are salt and pepper.
[Umi] Only salt and pepper on these,
and over here…
These seasonings add flavor.
[Shizu] Awesome.
[Chaka] You covered it in red flakes.
[Umi] In Japan, the opportunities to cook
like this are few and far between.
-This is called "seasoning."
-[Shizu] Seasoning?
Looks good. It adds flavor.
Think it's ready for the grill?
[Chaka, Shizu] Let's do it.
Meat's on the grill!
-[Chaka cheers]
-Whoa, it's sizzlin'!
-Sounds great! [chuckles]
-[Shizu chuckles]
[Umi] Yeah, we can't keep the noise down.
-Next.
-[Chaka] Yeah.
[Shizu, Umi, Chaka] Yeah! Yay!
[in English] Let's go!
There you go!
-[in Japanese] I win.
-[in English] There you go.
Isn't BBQ crazy awesome?
It's super.
[Chaka] And to be grilling meat
amidst this grand view…
-That's the nice part.
-This can't get any better.
[Umi] Is it done?
Let's turn it over.
[Chaka] I'll leave the rest
to our meat lover.
Can you chop it?
Do you want to use this one?
-That one?
-I think this one's meant for it.
-Shizu.
-Hmm?
Use this to snap it in half.
-You got it? Is it done?
-Yeah, cool.
I'll use my samurai sword.
[laughs]
We'll save the samurai sword
for next time.
[Noel] Shizuya's always said
he wants to try camping.
He's expressed interest
in outdoor activities
like survival retreats and camps.
He's always said he wants
to challenge himself to an activity
where it's just you against the wild.
That's why
I absolutely want him to go camping.
[Shizu] ♪ Toss the rest in the pot ♪
This is as hot as it gets.
It may not boil.
That salmon looks fantastic.
[Noel] Regarding Chaka…
Well, this is just my opinion of him.
I believe he wants to live life…
on his own terms, deep down.
As the leader of Travis Japan,
he's expected
to be the most responsible one.
I think he tends to put
too much on his shoulders.
I want him
to let loose a little.
Umi's the type to strongly object
to spending a night outdoors.
I want him to experience it just once
before he dismisses the idea completely.
He's a flexible guy.
He goes out with friends a lot,
but at the same time,
he's always struck me
as somewhat of an introvert
when it comes to hobbies and interests.
Comin' off the grill!
Whoa!
What a piece.
I'm drowning in the juicy goodness.
Sweet. I may have grilled
the best steak of my life.
[Shizu] Looks done.
Here, Chaka-chin.
[Chaka] Done!
Pasta's ready.
[Shizu] Welcome to my pasta shop.
[in English] Cheers!
-Cheers!
[♪ uplifting music plays]
[exclaims]
Everyone at once.
[all] Time to dig in.
[Umi] Wanna do the honors, Shizuya?
I'm free to address any of the other four?
Oy, Genta… This is heaven
in my mouth! Yum! [grunts]
[in English] Happy!
[Umi, in Japanese] It's super tasty.
Yo, Kaito.
Wanna know how it is?
It's freaking delicious.
This last bite's for Noel and Shime.
Ha! [chuckles]
Delicious!
We've got a mushroom
and broccoli pepperoncino.
Pepperoncini!
With a Utah spin.
Yum. Hmm.
[Umi] The pepperoncino.
It's freaking good.
It's yummy.
[Shizu] Yummy in my tummy!
-Yum.
-[Shizu] Makes me happy.
[Chaka] It's a good combination.
With barbecue.
-[Shizu] Is it?
-[Chaka] Hmm.
This is simply the best.
Simply the best?
It's simply
the best pasta I've had in my life.
That makes me smile.
-You cooked it for us.
-[Shizu chuckles]
Everything is good.
We started our trip to Moab…
-by having to locate it on a map.
-Yeah.
But now we're taking it all in.
Now we know
all about its fossils and the rocks.
We also experienced the culture out here.
Although this is
our first time camping ever,
-here we are barbecuing out in the nature.
-[chuckles] Ain't that something?
-It's still hard to believe.
-This all… Feels so surreal.
-Yeah.
-Moab brought us so many new experiences.
Yeah.
It's nice, being out in nature.
Yeah, I like nature.
I also enjoyed
all the encounters we've had
with the kind-hearted locals
who live out here.
[Chaka] Yeah.
Well…
Thanks for taking us to Moab.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
Translated by Megumi Hunter